viart.com 2014-11-22

# ViArt Software Privacy Policy

**Data Protection** | [](http://www.viart.com/#top)  
---|---  
  
ViArt Software are committed to protecting your privacy. We use the information we collect about you to process orders and to provide a more personalised shopping experience. 

**Collection & Use Of Information** | [](http://www.viart.com/#top)  
---|---  
  
When you order, we need to know your name, e-mail address, delivery address, credit or debit card number and start, expiry or issue date. This allows us to process and fulfil your orders and to notify you of your order status.

We also ask for your telephone number which enables us to contact you urgently if there is a problem with your order.

When you enter a competition or promotional feature, we may ask for your name, address and e-mail address so we can administer the contest and notify winners.

We also monitor customer traffic patterns and site usage to help us develop the design and layout of the site.

We may also use the information we collect to occasionally notify you about important functionality changes to the web site, new services and special offers we think you'll find useful. If you would rather not receive this information, please send an email to [nomail@viart.com](mailto:nomail@viart.com)

We do not send random marketing emails to personal email addresses (spam).

**Protection Of Customer Information** | [](http://www.viart.com/#top)  
---|---  
  
When you place orders or access your order information, we offer the use of a secure server. The secure server software (SSL) encrypts all information you input before it is sent to us.

Furthermore, as required by the Data Protection Acts of 1984 and 1998, we follow strict security procedures in the storage and disclosure of information which you have given us, to prevent unauthorised access.

Our security procedures mean that we may occasionally request proof of identity before we are able to disclose sensitive information to you.

**"COOKIES"** | [](http://www.viart.com/#top)  
---|---  
  
"Cookies" are small pieces of information that are stored by your browser on your computer's hard drive. Our cookies enable us to store items in your shopping basket between visits.

Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually change your browser to prevent that. Even without a cookie, you can still enjoy our site, but certain of the advanced features designed to enhance your visit will not be available to you.

For a full technical explanation of cookies, see Netscape's cookie specification at:  
<http://www.netscape.com/newsref/std/cookie_spec.html>

**Disclosure Of Information** | [](http://www.viart.com/#top)  
---|---  
  
ViArt Software does not sell, trade or rent your personal information to others. We may choose to do so in the future with trustworthy third parties, but you can tell us not to by sending a blank email message to [nomail@viart.com](mailto:nomail@viart.com).

ViArt Software may also provide aggregate statistics about our customers, sales, traffic patterns and related site information to reputable third-party vendors, but these statistics will include no information that will identify individuals.

Where there is sufficient evidence to suggest that fraud is being perpetuated, we reserve the right to pass data to other businesses, fraud databases and relevant authorities.

**Your Consent** | [](http://www.viart.com/#top)  
---|---  
  
By using our web site, you consent to the collection and use of this information by ViArt Software. If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on this page so that you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it and under what circumstances we disclose it.

**Privacy Policy Contact** | [](http://www.viart.com/#top)  
---|---  
  
If you have any queries with regard to our privacy policy, you may contact us at [privacy@viart.com](mailto:privacy@viart.com)
